Kourosh Arbabi, M.Eng

6538 Nelson Avenue, Burnaby, BC, V5H 0G5 Koorosh.arbabi@gmail.com 438-680-5817

Summary

Passionate and enthusiastic Engineer-In-Training with more than 3 years of Engineering experience. Embraces modern principles in Engineering, experienced in Assisting project management team, Project coordination, Cost Estimating, Navisworks, MS Project, Bluebeam, Procore, Fieldwire and MS Office.

Skills

Bluebeam

 Microsoft Office: Word, Excel, PowerPoint • On-Screen Takeoff

Autodesk: AutoCAD

Experience

Assistant Project Manager

May 2024 - Present

EllisDon Corporation – Oakridge Redevelopment – Vancouver

- Chair OAC meetings to discuss areas of concern, provide updates on project progress and address client concerns.
- Perform regular site walk with subcontractors and in collaboration with site superintendent to ensure adherence to project drawings and specifications and to be notified about any delays/concerns raised by subcontractors.
- Assist in identifying potential project risks, delays, and issues as well as prepare delay notices to client/subcontractors.
- Work with construction manager to develop mitigation strategies and action plans to minimize project disruptions caused by delays.
- Review site instructions and identify impacted scopes of work. Work with project coordinators to communicate site instructions with subcontractors involved and prepare change requests for submission to ownership.
- Conduct schedule analysis and any potential delay caused by the issuance of site instructions and provide the results to scheduling team to be reflected on project master schedule.
- Track and process subcontractors progress billing to ensure claimed values corresponds to correct budget line and are in line with site progress. Attend pencil draw meetings to review progress claims with owner representatives and their financial team.
- Maintain quality control of the project. Perform regular site walks to ensure subcontractor work has been executed per company's QA/QC guidelines and specification requirements. Distribute ITP and QA/QC documents and document testing and inspection reports conducted by third parties.
- Ensure the project complies with all safety regulations and industry standards. participate in safety meetings and assist the implementation of safety procedures and risk mitigation strategies.

EllisDon Corporation – Oakridge Redevelopment – Vancouver

- Assist with the procurement and operation team to execute the construction of a 4 million square foot mixed-used project including commercial, residential, office, community and cultural facilities, and transit service with a value of approximately \$2.2 billion dollars.
- Prepare project tender packages including subcontractor specific scope of work, construction schedule, drawings and specifications and communicate project updates such as Addenda, response to RFIs or any site instructions issued during the tender period with the bidders.
- Prepare bid result analysis spreadsheet for project management team review and subsequently draft letter of recommendations for ownership approval.
- Prepare trades' CCDC2 contracts upon the issuance of letter of authorization by ownership.
- Assist shop drawings review and approval, coordinate in-situ mockups and organize subcontractors' site orientation meetings.
- Track latest set of drawings and specifications as they are developed by the architect during the course of construction.
- Track and process subcontractors progress billings against the allocated budget for the specific scope of work.
- Ensure the project execution is in accordance with the milestones specified on schedule and report potential delays and deviations from the construction schedule critical paths to the project manager.
- Coordinate delivery of construction material with superintendents and site logistic team.

Project Coordinator/ Junior Estimator Willow Spring Construction - Surrey Project Coordinator

September 2021 - May 2022

- Worked closely with Project Manager and Superintendent in overall project management tasks including RFI's, Shop drawing review and transmittals, processing monthly invoices and releasing holdbacks, preparing weekly progress reports, preparing NOPs, subcontract administering. Develop project concepts and maintain optimal workflow.
- Helped manage the purchase order and change order process, including pricing, negotiating, processing, and assessing costs and schedule impact prior to reviewing with Project Manager.
- Prepare project close out documents including warranty package, walkthrough deficiency document, providing schedule B, C-B, etc. to be reviewed during inspection walkthrough.

Junior Estimator:

- Reported to the Chief Estimator and work as part of the estimating team on a wide variety of commercial tenant Improvement and landlord work projects between \$1m to \$20m in value.
- Attended tender site meetings and prepare site pictures and addenda provided by the client
- Performed quantity take-offs for all disciplines
- Sent tender invitations to contractors, maintain and develop relationships with sub-trades and clients
- Analyzed the quotes submitted by the sub-trades and make a note of all excluded items

Project Coordinator

May 2021 - September 2021

MNG Builders LTD - Vancouver

- Assist with the development and execution of the overall work plan and schedule to ensure deliverables are completed and project requirements and deadlines are met
- Contribute to the provision of job cost reports to ensure the progress of the project is in accordance with the allocated budget.
- Ensure works performed by subcontractors comply with drawings and specifications of the project

Education

Master of Engineering/Civil Engineering Concordia University - Montréal

January 2019 - January 2021

Bachelor of Science/Civil Engineering Azad University - Iran

September 2013 – September 2017

Certificates

VRCA – Construction Law

September 2023

Vancouver Regional Construction Association

Fall protection

August 2022

Halland Learning – Credential ID 11540